so let's see if we can figure out what
the directory will be doing in a mosc
protocol if we have four cores numbered
zero through three
and if the directory slice for location
a is in slice zero
if what happens is this core 0 reads a
core 0 writes a core 1
reads a
core 2
core 3 reads a and then core 0
writes a again
the question for you is
in this sequence of accesses assuming
that a is
not in any of the caches at the
beginning of this how many
requests are sent by these caches to the
directory only counting the requests
then the directory forwards these
requests through how many messages note
that it need not be the same number here
as a result of sending these the
directory gets how many responses and
replies
and finally how many responses does the
directory send itself again the protocol
is more ec for this course
and we have a directory protocol with
four cores